The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Tenth Episode
The Dangerous Doll
Prince Franz, shame on you!
A noble of your rank
yawning like that..!
I am so sorry! Last
night I read until late.
Watch how you behave
when we are ashore.
You are a Prince and
everyone will be watching you!
Grand Duke Duralumin,
where is the Prince, my son?
He went for a walk,
Sire.
Unfortunately, Sapphire
always embarrasses me.
On the other hand, Franz is a fine Prince!
Welcome
to our lands, dear Charles V!
We are pleased to see you again
after such a long time.
And so Prince Franz
has disappeared?
It seems so! He too had been
invited as a guest to court!
One does not disregard etiquette like this!
His father is very displeased about it!
I like him
and I'm going to look for him too!
You cannot! First you must greet
Charles V! Wait!
Don't worry so much
about etiquette!
Tell them I've disappeared too!
Stop! You cannot do that!
Ah, the youth of today!
Are you ready, Opal?
Let's go, little horse!
Sapphire, I'm here!
Take me with you, please!
Sapphire must have come
to this town.
Who knows where he went...! I'll ask
someone if they've seen him.
Is anyone there?
How strange, it seems empty.
What did I bump into?
And what is this?
By the look of it, it seems to be a doll
This way, please.
- Is this the mechanical doll?
- Yes, Grand Duke.
It wasn't easy to make it, but in the
end the result is... remarkable!
Just think, I had to
bring from a far-off country.
...a master puppeteer
to build it for me.
Enough chatter!
Can you assure me this doll
will serve to kill Sapphire?
Yes, of course, Grand Duke!
This time we will not fail,
if Sapphire watches the carnival
from the seat he reserved.
Do you know it walks?
In its stomach there is a boiler.
...that boils the water.
The steam that is released...
...drives an engine that allows her
to move and to walk.
- Ingenious, isn't it?
- Yes, not bad, not bad
I'm wondering if this doll
also talks.
- No. - It would be fantastic
if she could.
It would be the best invention
of all time.
Damn!
But then she can talk!
But it wasn't her,
because she can't talk!
- That's who it was!
- They saw me!
Wait, little one!
Thank goodness!
Don't move!
Where could he have got to?
He can't have gone far.
I can't find him.
Yet he must be here
Damned kid!
I won't let him escape from here!
- I'll stop you!
- Help! Help, he wants to kill me!
Oh, no!
What beautiful fireworks!
What a blow!
- Prince Sapphire!
- Prince Franz!
I see you've escaped from the castle.
Listen, here in town they are celebrating
carnival! Shall we go see?
As you wish.
Don't you think it's better to stay here?
- Yes, you're absolutely right!
- You should go out every now and then.
In the city there are
a lot of fun things!
I don't have much time.
Almost everything I have...
...I need to prevent
Nylon and Duralumin...
...from carrying out
their evil plans.
Don't think about it!
When we are Kings, we won't
be able to have fun anymore.
Oh, I just thought of something!
Here, it's for you!
Come on, take it!
I bought it before I
left. I think you'll like it.
What is this?
It's a mirror! It's for
looking at yourself.
I heard
that maybe you are a girl.
It will come in handy,
if you really are!
You really are a fool,
Prince Franz!
Who are you, dressed
in such funny clothes?
We are a group of masked
revelers and we are going around...
...celebrating Carnival.
Come with us, too!
Yes, come with us!
No! No, please!
Please! I don't want to!
Magnificent! It's the
most beautiful costume!
- It's number one!
- The best of the costumes!
I feel a bit uncomfortable
dressed up like this.
And now we're off to town.
Who could that beautiful
girl with the long hair be?
She's enchanting!
I must try to meet her.
Excuse me, may I have this dance?
Someone is galloping this way!
They're soldiers!
What do they want?
His Majesty is pleased to invite
you to the ball at the royal castle!
- His Majesty!
- His Majesty is truly generous!
Where could she have
gone? I can't find her!
Excuse me, have you seen
a young girl with long hair?
- No, I haven't seen anyone like that.
- And you, sir?
No, I haven't seen her either.
And yet I am sure that she too
is here, somewhere.
Baron Nylon, what have you done
with that boy you captured?
I locked him in the building
where the doll is,
so tomorrow he too will end up
together with Sapphire!
Those two are plotting
to kill Sapphire!
I must look for him immediately and
warn him of the danger he is in!
Do you have any idea where
our two offspring might be?
There's no need to worry, they must be
having fun somewhere.
- Oops!
- Please, Prince! Have mercy!
Now you will play something
more cheerful!
As you wish, Prince!
At your command!
Look at Sapphire, up to
one of his usual tricks!
As cheeky as ever!
Maestro, I told you to play
more cheerful music.
More than this?
We are still not there!
I would like it more elegant
What the hell can we play?
- Sapphire!
- Who is calling me?
I am here, Sapphire!
Can you come? I have to talk to you!
What do you have to tell me that is so important?
I caught Baron Nylon
and Grand Duke Duralumin...
while they were talking about killing you
- It's no surprise!
- What?!
Yes, it is nothing new to me!
It is always the same story.
They were also talking about that child
called Tink...
...and that, if I'm not
mistaken, is a friend of yours.
They said they are keeping him
prisoner in a building outside the city.
Good heavens! What are you saying?
I will start looking for
him from this house!
Tink, are you here? Tink!
I think I can make out the
shapes of strange puppets.
Tink, answer! Are you here?
What a huge doll!
Tink! Tink, can you hear me?
Answer! Are you in here, Tink?
It seems that in here
he is not.
I'll go look for him somewhere else.
Dear Baron, I can't wait for
this doll to go into action.
Me too, Grand Duke!
I will show you something.
Do you see that wire?
As soon as the doll's head
is level with that wire,
its mechanism will fire a shot
right at Sapphire's chest!
But do you think the Prince
will stand still...
...until the doll
has passed?
Don't worry! Together with the
doctor, I've worked out a little trick.
So, Sapphire, tell me: did you
manage to find that friend of yours?
Not yet. I've looked for him all
day, but there is no sign of him.
You've reminded me
that I must go back and look for him!
Stay seated, Your Highness!
You promised me...
...that you would be a good
Prince for the whole day.
You're right, I promised you.
I'll stay in my seat.
Where am I?
Judging by the construction,
I must be
inside the doll!
I'm pretty sure it's moving!
In the doll's mouth
I have placed a bow...
...ready to shoot his arrow that
will strike Sapphire in the heart!
A single shot will be enough, Grand Duke!
Maybe I understand.
Sapphire, you are in danger! Sapphire!
Damn it, he can't hear me!
Sapphire, be careful! Sapphire!
The time has come! Here we go!
She has stopped!
Sapphire has been hit!
- It worked!
- It killed my son!
Sapphire, the arrow hit you!
It didn't do anything to me, as
you can see! Your mirror saved me!
Guards!
Destroy that damn puppet!
- Yes, King!
- Help me! Pull me up!
I'll show you!
Damned giant puppet!
Come on!
Hey, stop! What do you want to do?!
There he is!
Opal!
I must stop
that crazy doll!
There it is!
Now I'm inside!
- Thank heaven, you're alive!
- Tink! What are you doing in here?
I was captured
by Baron Nylon!
- Then the doll is his!
- Yes, he wanted to kill you!
We must destroy it!
Just break the boiler!
Do you mean this one?
Watch out, it might explode!
Quick, Sapphire! It's heading
towards the castle!
I will help you stop it!
Raise the drawbridge!
What's happening now?
It is trying
to destroy the castle!
It's dangerous to stay here!
Let's go outside!
- Tink!
- Here I am!
Run as fast as you can!
You know, Franz, without your gift
I would have died! You saved me!
And I apologize to you: I won't
treat you like a girl anymore.
- Thank you!
- During the carnival
I met a girl
who had long hair...
...and she was so pretty!
I hope to see her again, one day.
She has remained in my heart!
Goodbye, Sapphire!
If you happen to meet
that girl,
tell her that I will return for her!
See you soon,
dear Sapphire!
Goodbye, Franz! I really think
that I will meet that girl.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP